# James Han

## Full Stack Developer

🔀 jameshan044@gmaill.com 😲 Manseau QC, Canada 📢 apple0441

#### **Profile**

Full stack developer with over 7+ years of experience in Java/JS, Angular, Vue, React, Python, Node.js. In improving user engagement by 7.5%, reducing development and deployment time by 20% and mentoring junior developers, resulting in a 10% improvement in team satisfaction scores. I have also good experience of teamwork.

## **Professional Experience**

#### Full Stack Developer, Swiftype ☑

03/2020 - 05/2023 | Remote

- Engineered a membership platform from scratch using MERN; increased retention rate by 5% and saved the company 10 hours of manual work per week
- Researched and created a new application to be used by the company, resulting in a 1.2x increase in sales
- Generated \$500K+in annual ad revenue as a system administrator of a large network of websites.
- Developed a node.js server to validate membership and track digital badges being used, saving the company \$22.5K.
- · Mentored 4 team members, enabling them to achieve professional growth and personal goals
- Developed the process of testing and recording the results of the test, thereby increasing the number of tests completed per day by 10%

## **Full Stack Developer,** Straight North

01/2018 - 02/2020 | Baltimore, US

- Fostered a culture of collaboration within the team by implementing agile methodologies, leading to a 10% increase in project efficiency and a 5% reduction in time-to-market
- Designing a new web application to enhance collaboration between design, engineering and sales teams increased revenue by 10% in one quarter.
- Built a custom web application for a major client, successfully delivering an integrated CRM system in just 2 weeks
- Developed a new technique for reducing the time it takes to fix crashes by 20%

## Junior Web Developer, Fareportal

11/2015 - 12/2017 | New York, US

- Designed and implemented a new cloud-based mobile POS platform, resulting in a 2.5% increase in customer retention
- Coordinated cross-functional teams of hardware and software developers to ensure seamless integration of the new POS system; achieved 10% reduction in transaction processing time
- Continued to develop specialty skills related to his expertise in mobile POS and payment technologies
- Developed and continuously improved an internal knowledge base of best practices for software development

#### **Education**

#### **Bachelor of Computer Science,**

09/2011 - 11/2015 | Kowloon, Hong Kong

Hong Kong University of Science and Technology 

☑

## **Skills**

<b>MERN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js	••••	<b>MEAN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, React, Node.js	••••
<b>MEVN</b> MongoDB, Express.js, Vue.js, Node.js	••••	<b>Django</b> (HTML, CSS, JS/TS, python)	••••
<b>Database</b> MySQL, Oracle, MongoDB, NoSQL	••••	<b>Cloud</b> Firebase, Cloudflare, AWS	••••
Figma	••••	Others Python, C/C++, C#/.NET, WordPress, Larave	• • • • •

#### Languages

English	$\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$ $\bullet$	Chinese	
---------	---	---------	--